<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Toxip</title>
    <description>My homepage</description>
    <link>https://toxip.net/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://toxip.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 04:20:34 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 04:20:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The purpose of likes in Twitter</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I haven’t been a twitter user for too long but long enough to see some of the biggest changes in the platform. I started using twitter in 2013 when I got my first Jolla phone because Sailfish OS provided a nice twitter integration where I could read the twitter timeline without the need to enter the app itself. It was handy to be able to take a quick glance at what people were talking about in the world. I fell in love with the platform because of how it worked as a source for curated content without giving you the information overload thanks to the 140 character limit. Retweet is a brilliant way of spreading the interesting content in the network but ever since day one I was wondering what the purpose of likes (or favorites back then) is in Twitter. Guys at Twitter must have been wondering the same thing since tecently Twitter has introduced a new feature that displays tweets that people you’re following like. Now to understand why this is a problem I’ll go over the basic features of Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter’s revolutionary idea was to be able to spread information in a tightly packed format. At first it may have seemed weird to artificially limit the amount of information you can spread with a character limit but in a society where we drown in information it makes a lot of sense. The character limit made people think twice what they’re gonna write and effectively filter all the useless stuff out - kind of like writing abstracts. While the character limit was probably the defining feature, Twitter also provided nice tools to help information spread among its users like retweets, hashtags and follows. All this worked together to provide a platform for strong content curation. People tweet and retweet stuff that they find interesting or newsworthy and you can choose to follow them if you find the content interesting. You have the power to build yourself a timeline &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; like and again spread that information forward. You can mix in hashtags that will help connect with others who are interested in the same subjects. And all this in a completely public forum. This curation system is in my opinion the very core of the whole system that makes twitter so appealing. But where do the likes (favorites) come in? I don’t know about the others but I never found a real use for them. While all the other features worked together to improve content curation in the platform, likes were just more numbers on a screen. Maybe the only time they could contribute to the whole system would be when you check someone’s profile who liked your tweets but I don’t think that’s very useful. Before the likes were still called favorites, it was maybe even less evident. People hardly knew what favorite meant since they it didn’t really function like favorite does in many other apps. Now that they’re likes, people seem to just like stuff they find funny.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 15:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://toxip.net/technology/2017/11/04/the-purpose-of-likes-in-twitter.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://toxip.net/technology/2017/11/04/the-purpose-of-likes-in-twitter.html</guid>
        
        <category>twitter</category>
        
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Jekyll!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:06:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://toxip.net/jekyll/update/2017/04/20/welcome-to-jekyll.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://toxip.net/jekyll/update/2017/04/20/welcome-to-jekyll.html</guid>
        
        <category>test1</category>
        
        <category>test2</category>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
